<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<CodeplexIssue xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Id>19965</Id>
  <Title>Address Property of Range Object has no parameters (NetOffice 1.6.0)</Title>
  <DescriptionHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[I tried migrating my .NET application (Microsoft Excel Add-In) from NetOffice Release 1.4.1 to 1.6.0 (latest), and am experiencing an error with my code. Specifically, the Address property of the Range object appears not to have any parameters ie. Address()
 - May I please know if this is intended? For your reference, I am currently working with .NET 2.0.

Thank you in advance.]]></DescriptionHtml>
  <Status>Proposed</Status>
  <Type>Unassigned</Type>
  <Impact>Unassigned</Impact>
  <Comments>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>SebastianDotNet</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[do you use Visual Basic? (VB has a syntax issue here, you need the get_ version)


Sebastian]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2013-07-15T13:48:17.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>eugene_huang</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[Hi Sebastian, 

Thank you for your prompt response. Yes, I'm working with Visual Basic and your solution worked perfect. Thank you again.


I now, however, experience another error when I run my compiled add-in on Microsoft Excel (Please refer to the attached file for the error messages). This error does not occur when I run my other compiled .NET applications (Microsoft Word, Microsoft PowerPoint
 Add-Ins), which have also been migrated from NetOffice 1.4.1 to 1.6.0. Please let me know if I should raise this as a separate issue on the discussion board.


For your reference, I am testing the compiled add-in on Microsoft Excel 2007, Windows Vista.


Thank you again. 

Eugene]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2013-07-15T15:33:44.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>SebastianDotNet</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[did you use the netoffice tools namespace?]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2013-07-15T16:35:46.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>eugene_huang</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[Pardon my ignorance; I'm not entirely familiar with namespaces. I don't believe I used the "netoffice tools namespace" but I may have done so unknowingly. Is there anyway I can check to find out?


To let you know, I am using the Assemblies:1. ExcelApi.dll2. NetOffice.dll3. OfficeApi.dll4. PowerPointApi.dll5. VBIDEApi.dll6. WordApi.dll


Thanks again.]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2013-07-16T15:15:18.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>SebastianDotNet</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[no worries. the tools namespace is a new 1.6 feature.as first try to debug the problem.go the menu debugging/exceptions and activate the checkbox 'Common Language Runtime Exceptions' now go to the project properties/debugging and hit the option 'start
 external program' and choose your office application(path)now start debugging and see where the exception occurs in your code


Sebastian]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2013-07-16T22:57:14.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>eugene_huang</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[Sebastian, 

Thank you for your advice. 

The error appears to result from the following block of code: 

Dim excelProxy As Object = System.Runtime.InteropServices.Marshal.GetActiveObject("Excel.Application")Dim xlApp As Excel.Application = New Excel.Application(Nothing, excelProxy)


The precise error message is attached to this message, for your reference. 

I really appreciate your help and patience with this. 

Eugene]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2013-07-17T16:38:10.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>SebastianDotNet</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[the error occurs in which line ??the last ?? :o ( the assert message tolds me you try to call a method.N0 doesnt use Debug.Assert btw. you do?*scary]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2013-07-18T14:47:15.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>eugene_huang</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[I've tried testing it again, and can now confirm that the error occurs in the following line:


Dim xlApp As Excel.Application = New Excel.Application(Nothing, excelProxy) 

Yes, I used "Debug.Assert" to debug the code as I have difficulty doing so through Visual Studio (dll is called by vba). Is there is any way I can circumvent this? I tried debugging on Visual Studio using the instructions you provided (ie. specified
 excel as an external program), but nothing happens when I hit "debug" (an instance of Excel starts up but nothing happens thereafter).


Thank you again.]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2013-07-18T15:30:17.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>SebastianDotNet</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[its possible that your vba code is executed while excel is starting? 

about the debugging: can you tell me your target .net version and vs version?]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2013-07-18T17:45:46.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>eugene_huang</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[I deleted the VBA files (which run on excel startup) prior to debugging, so it's unlikely the VBA files were interferring with the debugging process.


My target .NET version is 2.0, and I'm working with Visual Studio Express 2008.]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2013-07-19T13:33:43.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>eugene_huang</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[Hi Sebastian, 

May I please know if you've had the chance to review my query? Please let me know there's any additional information you require.


Thank you,Eugene]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2013-07-28T11:20:51.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>SebastianDotNet</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[when its possible, please send me your solution (incl. the netoffice binaries u use) to public.sebastian[at]web.de, remove all privat code you if want and give me instructions how i can reproduce your scenario.


Sebastian]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2013-07-28T12:21:54.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
  </Comments>
  <ReportedBy>eugene_huang</ReportedBy>
  <ReportedAt>2013-07-14T07:35:43.0000000+00:00</ReportedAt>
</CodeplexIssue>