<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<CodeplexIssue xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Id>21962</Id>
  <Title>cannot access to Rows property in ExcelAPI</Title>
  <DescriptionHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[Hi,
I'm a new user of net office and I'm trying to make a ribbon addin to Excel. It's kind of a proof of concept to show it is possible to make a real powerfull/clean/maintainable development using .NET instead of writing tons of vba code (using sharpdevelop).
One of the basic feature I'm trying to show is to select a row in a sheet, click on a button and then insert a row just underneath the one selected.
You could write it in vba like this:
Selection.Rows.insert()
But I can't find any Rows property (nor any Columns property) in Worksheet class (can't find it anywhere else). Then I tried to find methods provided by ExcelAPI DLL; I just found that Rows property exist but that Browsable attribute has been set to false.
Is this expected? If so, how can I access that property to insert a row where I want?

thank you]]></DescriptionHtml>
  <Status>Proposed</Status>
  <Type>Unassigned</Type>
  <Impact>Unassigned</Impact>
  <Comments>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>SebastianDotNet</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[have you tried get_Rows? (in some situations visual basic has problems to the see properties from c# code)


*Sebastian]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2015-08-06T20:49:33.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>pasielsky</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[I'm using CSharp in Sharpdevelop. Intellisense does not provide any Rows nor Columns properties. Again, using ildasm on Excel API DLL, it shows me a method called Rows but I can see its browsable attribute has been set to false.I'm using net office 1.7.3get_Rows
 is unavailable as well.]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2015-08-06T22:55:45.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>SebastianDotNet</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[Currently, the Rows property is hidden. same for columns. (i want clearify why it is...)in other words you can use them but Intellisense wont show it.


i want remove the hidden annotations for the properties immediately.please let me know if you find some more...


*Sebastian]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2015-08-07T02:18:47.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>pasielsky</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[I can tell that EntireRow and EntireColumn properties from Range class are not browsable as well]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2015-08-07T16:39:39.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
    <CodeplexComment>
      <Author>SebastianDotNet</Author>
      <BodyHtml xml:space="preserve"><![CDATA[thx!Rows and Columns has been changed.i want change EntireRow and EntireColumn today.


*Sebastian]]></BodyHtml>
      <CreatedAt>2015-08-08T09:54:44.0000000+02:00</CreatedAt>
    </CodeplexComment>
  </Comments>
  <ReportedBy>pasielsky</ReportedBy>
  <ReportedAt>2015-08-05T10:49:32.0000000+00:00</ReportedAt>
</CodeplexIssue>